Barak Cohen

Javascript Developer

052-5797294 baaraak0@gmail.com github.com/baaraak linkedin.com/in/barak-cohen92/

About me

I'm passionate front end engineer with experience developing complex, high profile web applications collaborating with both small and large teams. I specialise in JavaScript, familiar with the agile environment and leveraging modern technologies such as React and Redux. Familiar with server-side languages like Node.js and PHP.

Experience

2020 - Current

After I left Amdocs for travelling and being on military reserve duty due to COVID-19.
I had to care for a family member after an injury.
Since then, I'm fully available to work now.

Amdocs

Software Engineer - React.js Developer (Nov 2017 - Aug 2019)

- Build complex enterprise level micro-service front end applications from scratch using React.js and redux.
- Experience with UI/UX design, optimize across various screen sizes and cross-browser.
- · Writing unit tests using Jest and Enzyme.
- Design and implement crucial business features.
- · Working in agile methodology.
- CI/CD process with Jenkis and kubernetes.
- Working with Node.js and AWS.

Techfinancials - Herzliya

Fullstack Developer - PHP, React.js (May 2016 - Oct 2017)

- Rewrite the frontend application from scratch using React.js and Node.
- Build responsive web and mobile web applications from scratch.
- Design and develop new business features.
- · Create new WordPress themes and plugins.
- Scrum master, control over the agile process in the team.

Skills

- JavaScript
- Node.js
- CSS / SCSS / CSS-IN-JS
- CI/CD

- React
- Redux, Redux-thunk/saga/toolkit
- Typescripts
- · Webpack, Babel, Gulp
- Enzyme, Jest, Cypress

- Docker
- · Responsive Design
- Mysql, MongdoDB
- GraphQL, Apollo
- Wordpress

Education

Full-stack web development.

HackerU College

- Full stack web development at HackerU college.
- PHP, MySQL, Laravel, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, SEO.

Languages

- Hebrew Fluent.
- English Good.